People of God, Emmanuel!
(God with us - Matthew 1:23)
Emmanuel!
God lives here.
I said God lives in the Synagogue.
My name is Mr Ume Chinedu Ambi.
The lovely lady with me is my lovely daughter, Elizabeth Numao Ume. She is a half Japanese.
Although we are from Japan, originally we are Nigerians living in Japan.
Our testimony goes like this:
We are here to disgrace the devil. We have a lot but let us start with the...
I mean how God delivered us from this generational curse, which is asthma.
I mean, it's precisely four years ago now, 2014 when we came here.
I came here with my daughter.
Before I say that, I think I have one confession to make.
And that confession is this: Each time our mentor, my mentor and your mentor,
Senior Prophet T.B. Joshua says that word, it always hits my heart.
He always says you are welcome.
"Over my dead body" - I think I was one of the people who was against this ministry.
Let me be sincere.
In fact, to the extent that I wouldn't even want somebody close to me
to mention T.B. Joshua or The Synagogue where I am.
I remember one time in Japan when I was... they were about to do a container for me
and there were about 3 or 4 guys and one of them just mentioned T. B. Joshua.
In fact I just called the owner of the place and said, "Please, can you just suspend this guy.
I don't want him to touch my stuffs".
To show you the extent I was against that...
Let me be sincere to tell the truth; I want to shame the devil.
I never believed that, the same man, the same place...
In fact people who are hearing me now because a lot of people know me in Japan -
I was the vice chairman of the Nigerian Chamber of Commerce
and I have a company MBG Global Company Japan Ltd.
I have almost 27 people working for me there.
But everybody, in fact I know most of them watching me now will say, "Hey, finally".
Each time now, as I'm talking to you here now, Emmanuel TV is on in Japan at my workplace.
I never play with it ever since I discovered this ministry.
The man I hated so much, I talked so much about him, against him.
Then what brought me here?
People of God, it's a long story but I have to make it short.
After the death of my mother; in fact that was 2007; I had burial rites for her in 2008.
Like I was talking about asthma, my mother died of the same sickness.
Right in my compound - it's a small compound in my village - here I buried my father,
immediate junior brother and the next my mother.
I never believed because in Japan I never believed anything, evil attacks.
Instead I told them, "Look, it's only in Nigeria you see people talking about spiritual attacks and the rest of it".
But people of God it was like:
After the death of my mother, I started experiencing spiritual attacks.
This attack was so enormous that they brought a coffin
and in that coffin, in fact each time I slept, they brought a coffin for me.
They said, "Look, you are the next person". They showed it on my compound.
They said, "Look, the fourth one is you". So I asked, "What is happening?
I ate in the dream, flew in the dream, spiritual wife.
To the extent that it was only my little daughter that was with me. Everybody left me.
My company, all the three shops, everything closed down.
There was nothing. What is happening?
In fact, the second time, the third time, my spirit left my body.
Let me just call this church because I cannot even...
Look, I am a dead person but I think I am alive because of this ministry.
Through this ministry...
Mr Chinedu & Daughter
New Morning Water Testimony
Through this ministry, God decided to give me a second chance to live again.
In fact when it was too much, the whole thing was too much, I couldn't...
The one thing that I couldn't believe was that I locked up all the doors.
How then did somebody, an old woman come into - this was not even in the dream.
It was live. An old woman came to my bed and slept on my bed,
I was like, "What is happening, after I prayed and everything?"
So when it was too much, I said, "Look, one thing I said I will not do
is to go and start to go to babalawo (witch doctor) but I have done everything humanly possible".
They took me to a spiritualist, they prayed for me. It didn't work, nothing worked.
Then I called my little brother who lives in Japan with me.
I told him, "Look, what I did was to write my will".
First, they said, "It's because you have not married. You need to get married".
I went to Nigeria, I got married three times but to no avail. All of them left.
Spirit of rejection, everything I touched. Everything, all my projects, everything stopped.
All my containers - I had three containers that were coming - everything seized, nothing.
I mean, this is not a contraband.
As I am talking to you, up to today, these containers are nowhere to be found.
What I did was I called my little brother. He came and I wrote my will.
I gave my will to my daughter.
I brought out my credit cards, all my passports and gave them to her.
I said, "I might leave anytime; any moment from now, I will go and join my ancestors".
Because there was no hope, no more hope. I had lost all hope.
So my little brother looked at me and I was crying, shedding tears right in my office.
He said, "Brother, let's go to your house". I said, "Why?" He said, "Let's go to your house".
When we got to my house, then he brought out... he just dipped inside his pocket.
Mr Chinedu & Daughter
New Morning Water Testimony
He brought out this. I said, "What is this?"
He said, "Brother, do you remember what you told me during December time
when I wanted to travel to the village?" - I had asked him not to go to village.
They needed somebody; they wanted to bury another person again.
He said, "Do you know what I did?" - I said, "What? Did you go to babalawo (witch doctor)?
I told you not to. You know me, I don't believe in all these babalawos (witch doctors)".
He said, "No, I got something that is bigger than babalawo (witch doctor)".
I said, "What is that?" He said, "This is it".
Mr Chinedu & Daughter
New Morning Water Testimony
So he said, "Brother, let us pray", and I closed my eyes.
You know, somebody who is about to die, you are now ready to accept anything.
Then we started praying.
Then he said, "Open your mouth"; I opened my mouth.
He just sprayed it two times.
Then he went around the whole house and sprayed the Morning Water.
After that he left.
Believe me, people of God, that very day, it was like the whole house was calm.
Mr Chinedu & Daughter
New Morning Water Testimony
All those noises - because from the other room I would hear noise, the other place,,,
The cats that used to cry every night beside my window - I never knew that cats cry like a baby -
everything subsided.
I said, "God, what is this. Can it be magic?"
Then I called him the next day.
I said, "Come. Bring that something for me".
Mr Chinedu & Daughter
New Morning Water Testimony
Because then, I never knew. I said, "Bring that magic for me again".
He said, "Brother, sorry". Now he came back. He brought it and said, "This is Morning Water".
I said nothing. He filled it with water and said, "Brother, have this one; start spraying it".
Believe me, when I sprayed it, I didn't hear anything again.
The next day I just went to YouTube and it said "Synagogue" and he came out.
I said, "This is the man that I hated so much. Can this be real?"
So what I did was...
A period before then, I had been operated two times of kidney cancer.
I then went to the hospital the next day.
When I got to the hospital - because after the operation, I kept on going to follow up -
the next thing after the test, the doctor said, "Look, it's confirmed, you are free from cancer".
Put your hands together beautifully for Jesus Christ!
I asked him, "Can I travel to Nigeria?" and he said, "Yes".
After the operation he had said I could not travel because of this.
So he now said, "You can travel".
I took the next available flight to Nigeria; I flew straight to The SCOAN.
But a significant thing happened that very day; there was one beautiful thing that happened.
Because that very day - that was in June, the man of God's birthday.
Everywhere was highly jam-packed; there was no space.
In fact, there was no space for me.
I was surprised; I was thinking it was just things you give out - you get easy access.
Right down at the overflow side, I sat down because there were too many people.
I sat down. All of a sudden, I was in a trance. Then I bent down my head.
The next thing I saw was - I saw Jesus standing in my front.
And there was an altar. The altar was in my front and Jesus was there.
Then I woke up and said, "Am I sleeping? Am I dreaming?"
Then the second time it happened, I stood up.
I walked round the whole compound and said, "God, what is going on?"
The next day, which was a Sunday, I was opportune to get into the church.
Then I discovered that it was exactly the same altar where I was kneeling down -
the same altar where I was kneeling down that very day.
I said, "God". Then I called my brother and said, "God is here".
I never knew that asthma... - I was told that asthma can never be cured because it is in the blood.
That was when I was told that asthma can be cured.
I just dashed out to go and bring my daughter.
In fact, people of God, after that...
Ok, tell us - what was the problem your daughter was having then
and what were the challenges she was facing?
In fact, the same asthma that took away my mother's life
was about to take even my own life and her own life too.
Her own was so severe that every month, we were in the hospital.
People who knew her in Ibadan, one of the American schools, ACA American Christian Academy,
they knew her very much at UCH because every month, she used to be in UCH -
they used to admit her at the University Teaching Hospital in Ibadan.
It was too much then - I spent money, I spent everything but to no avail.
There was a drug they said it was a drug from India. I ordered it.
We used it for almost 90 days with no oil, nothing but it was to no avail.
Then in Japan, there is one they call kampo yaku - that is in Japanese language - a traditional drug.
We used it to no avail.
I want her to talk for herself.
At the end of the day, I spent money, I spent everything but I tell you, people of God,
when we came down - no money, nothing.
We didn't pay a dime; it was just only the touch of the man of God.
Then, we continued to administer the Morning Water.
Before I knew it, up to today, my brethren, it is four years now; we have not been to any hospital again.
I want to tell people that Prophet T.B. Joshua...
I say it in Yoruba - agbanilagbatan - it is God that heals; when He heals, He heals completely.
I want to tell people that there is God.
If you are watching me here, just keep on - look to this altar, He is here.
Jesus is here. He lives here.
I said God lives in this Synagogue and everybody that knows me now knows that.
I said God of T.B. Joshua doesn't have peer.
I have travelled all over the world; I have travelled almost all continents.
As I am talking to you presently, if there is anywhere else you can tell me there is God,
please come and show me.
I was in Japan, I only just touched Emmanuel TV.
I mean, can you imagine - I can't fathom that.
How can you believe? How can you believe that only touching in Japan - as far as Japan?
I touched Emmanuel TV - in fact, I was shocked, "What is happening?"
So there is no any other God.
To God be the Glory. Put your hands together beautifully for the Miracle Worker Jesus Christ!
Testimony Time
People of God, Emmanuel!
(God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Elizabeth Ume. I am 17 years old and I am from Japan.
My problem goes like: I had asthma since when I was born.
I had a very severe asthma.
I was admitted into hospital almost every single month and I couldn't do a lot of things.
I couldn't do a lot of sports, activities and play around with my friends because of the asthma.
Sometimes, it was very difficult to have my education
because I was pulled out from school because of my severe asthma.
There was this time - it was very difficult for me to breathe in and breathe out.
So it was basically disabling me from a lot of things.
My dad took me to The SCOAN and it was my first time here.
I didn't know what was going on but I was just excited to be here because I love Africa so much.
When I came here, the man of God touched me and I fell down.
I didn't remember what was going on but I just fell down and then I woke up.
From that time, I was breathing just fine.
I was breathing totally fine.
Healed Of Asthma
Through The New Morning Water
I went back to Japan and since then, I have not been to the hospital.
I have not been admitted to the hospital again - not even once, not in my life.
I keep on administering this Morning Water.
From then, I have been so healthy; I haven't been having any asthma;
I haven't been having any difficulty in breathing.
Thank you to the Lord.
Wow. Put your hands together for what the Lord has done in the life of our sister.
My advice is that there are a lot of people in the world who don't know The SCOAN
and people don't really know God exists.
I just want to advise people that people should get to know God
and spread the Word of God so everybody in the world can know this.
Anybody that has asthma: I pray that they will come here to get healed.
Healed Of Asthma
Through The New Morning Water
My advice goes like this: I want to borrow a word from the Yoruba language -
and I will interpret it to you.
The meaning is this: Come and test and see that the Lord is good.
Those who are doubting - like those doubting Thomases like me before -
those who don't believe in The Synagogue;
those who don't believe there is God in Nigeria because some of us believe nothing could come...
Come and test. I am advising you to come. Just come.
Don't let anybody deceive you.
And those words - sometimes, you hear people saying all sort of things.
In fact it happened to me. "You know operations work" - people will tell you something.
But my brethren, I am a living witness; I am a living testimony. God is here.
There are other people I knew that I kept in contact with that knew something is happening here.
They knew but I see them as being jealous.
They are being jealous of what is happening - that God is using the man of God T.B. Joshua.
Or perhaps they are pastors, they have their own churches.
But I want to tell them that because the Bible is our standard
and God said, I will forgive every sin that a man committed but one.
And which sin is that? Sin against the Holy Spirit.
Because you know quite alright that the Holy Spirit is using the man of God; the Holy Spirit is here.
And you are now saying something evil.
You can even imagine that when somebody was healed here and he was called -
somebody called him from his church and said, "Leave that place".
Somebody who was healed.
So I want to tell you that please, the Bible is our standard.
I say, please, can you just desist from that; stop that
because God is not going to forgive you because that is sin against the Holy Spirit.
Thank you very much.
Mr Chinedu & Daughter
New Morning Water Testimony
The Morning Water is God Himself.
I used to tell people, "Look, I cannot do anything without the Morning Water - not even my food..."
No matter where I am going, anything I do...
I used to tell her, "This Morning Water, don't just...".
People of God, please, when you have it, make an altar for it and keep it there.
That's how I keep it - I have my altar where I keep my Morning Water; it's precious.
And God is here and God is still using the man of God.
God is using this man to heal the world.
We thank you very much for your wonderful advice and we also want to enjoin you that
as God Almighty has healed you, delivered you and set you free,
make sure you make God's Word the standard for your life
so that that healing you and your daughter have received will remain permanent, in Jesus' name.
Amen.
TT Monica Asefa 18/01/19
RV: Mel Flowers 24/01/2019